Preliminary Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. London Office. Records, 1920s-2005 and undated RL.00723
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Accession (2008-0270), 1920s-2005 and undated, 449 boxes
  - Office Records
    - JWT Procedures for Quality, JWT Quality Assurance Manual, McCrae Consultants, Lead Assessor Course (Box 36)
    - Management simulation seminar (Box 129)
    - Media: Asia-Pacific Media Forum; various media reports; children and television reports; IPA (International Practitioners of Advertising) radio study (Box 274)
    - Media Department (Box 256)
    - Media Department (Box 256A)
    - Media Department (Box 274)
    - Miscellaneous corporate correspondence (Box 47)
    - Miscellaneous office files (mostly policy & procedure) (Box 36)
    - Miscellaneous office files (Box 300)
    - Mostly photos from office party (Box 333)
    - Mostly photos from office party (Box 390A)
    - Old photographs (Box 169)
    - Personnel records (Box 46)
      [Restrictions on Access: All personnel files are closed for 40 years.]
    - Personnel records (Box 69)
    - Personnel records (Box 156)
    - Personnel records (Box 156A)
    - Personnel records (Box 254)
    - Report on retail technology (Box 41)
    - Reports: RBL Consumption Study, Representatives' Basic Reading List, Television consumer audit (Box 32)
    - Reports (Box 46)
    - Research--Brands (Box 390)
    - Research--Children, direct marketing, market research (Box 128A)
    - Research--Cooking, going out, entertaining in, recipes (Box 392)
    - Research--Flymo wet/dry vacuum cleaner; children and media (Box 128)
    - Research--Food, magazines, own label (Box 198)
    - Research--Private labels (Box 206)
    - Research--Sponsorship (Box 99)
    - Staff photographs and biographies, 1980s (Box 251)
    - Television sponsorship report (Box 26)
    - Thompson Way (Box 118)
    - Thompson Way (Box 232)
    - Training; Broadcast media; ITV (Box 189)
    - Training manuals (Box 215)
    - Videos: Brand is the Business, Dark Star, JWT showreel, Migrant Worker, Mike Leigh extracts, Miracle of Life (BBC) (Box 43)
    - Women, the Quiet Revolution (report) (Box 274)
    - WPP Group annual report (Box 43)
    - Photographs--Jeremy Bullmore (Box 394)
    - Photograph--Creative Department 1975 (Box 394)
  - General--Training, etc. (Box 294)
  - Knowledge Centre records
    - Card index, IPA papers, miscellaneous publications (Box 369)
    - Microfiche index (Box 380A)
    - Microfiche index (Box 380)
    - Microfiche index (Box 324)
    - Microfiche index (Box 317)
    - Knowledge Centre miscellaneous (Currency Profile, Le Torri Lombard VHS) (Box 138)
    - Knowledge Centre tapes (presentations, speeches, etc. 1970s-early 1990s) (Box 152)
    - Knowledge Centre: Institute of Practitioners in Advertising (IPA), IPA Prudential case study (Box 46)
    - Knowledge Centre: IPA (International Practitioners of Advertising), misc. files (Box 26)
    - Knowledge Centre: IPA (International Practitioners of Advertising), misc. files (Box 263)
    - Knowledge Centre: IPA Advertising Effectiveness entries (Box 354A)
    - Knowledge Centre: IPA Advertising Effectiveness entries (Box 354)
- Accession (2009-0112), 1978-2000 and undated, 2 boxes
  Contains materials from the Knowledge Centre: Kellogg's commercials on 11 Umatic tapes; Lipton, Unilever, Rowntree/Nestlé, Rolex and Manfield & Sons account files; financial records; TTB, WPP Atticus and Year in Review publications; Unilever/Knorr Chicken Tonight radio spots on CD; Umatic Jim Foster on Brouillard; VHS tape of DeBeers 1992 and Women's Attitude toward Cooking in Europe 2000.
  - Tapes and Miscellaneous from Room Behind Cleaners and Elsewhere (Box 1)
    - Account Files--Lipton (Box 1)
    - Account Files--Manfield & Sons (shoe company) (Box 1)
    - Account Files--Rolex (Box 1)
    - Account Files--Rowntree/Nestlé (Kit Kat) (Box 1)
    - Account Files--TSB (Box 1)
    - Account Files--Unilever (Box 1)
    - Audiovisual--DeBeers, 1992 (Box 1)
    - Audiovisual--Jim Foster/Brouillard, 1986 (Box 1)
    - Audiovisual--Knorr (Unilever) Chicken Tonight radio spots (Box 1)
    - Audiovisual--Women's Attitude to Cooking in Europe, 2000 (Box 1)
    - Guard Book records (Box 1)
    - London Office financial records (Box 1)
    - Publication--JWT Year in Review, 1998, 2000 (Box 1)
    - Publication--WPP Atticus (Box 1)
    - Stationery (Box 1)
    - Thompson Total Branding binder, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Audiovisual--Kellogg's commercials, 1978-1994 (11 tapes, Umatic) (Box 2)
- Accession (2002-0269), 1928-2001 and undated
  - A New Map for Europe, 1990 (Box 1)
  - CDs and a document relating to Thompson Total Branding Awards, 1998-2001 (Box 1)
    [Technical Services needs to reformat for use copies of CD-Rs before use.]
  - Staff pictures for biographies, 1990s (Box 1)
    [Attention: Contains pictorial materials.]
  - Surveys for Kellogg, 1959-1960 (Box 1)
  - Agency in Action, undated (Box 1)
    [Illustrated publication which gives background on the JWT London Office then located at Bush House, Aldwych.]
  - Scrapbook by the Ministry of Food, Home and women's magazine advertising, 1945 Aug.-1948 May (Box 2)
    [Assisted the public in coping with continued food rationing after World War II.]
  - Kellogg, Advertising and Promotion Recommendations, 1971-1973 (Box 2)
  - Rinso detergent scrapbook, 1931-1937 (Box 3)
  - Vaseline Soapless Shampoo scrapbook, 1936-1937 (Box 3)
  - Photographs of Jeremy Bullmore, 1975 (Box 3)
    [Part of the London Creative (?) Department. Attention: Contains pictorial materials.]
  - Oxo souvenir edition mock issue of the Daily Mirror tabloid, 1960 (Box 3)
    Original sketches and animation cells for commercials featuring Kellogg's Tony the Tiger
  - Proof books from JWT's Berlin, Germany Office1928-1938 (Box 3)
    [Includes Kraft, 1928; Horlick's, 1929 (2 books); Ponds, 1936-1938; Only known original proof books from this office; most print ads from that era outside the U.S. have survived only on microfilm that is in the JWT archives.]
- Accession (1998-0519), 1994-1995, 5 boxes
  Primarily tapes and transcripts of interviews done by Tom Rayfield with various JWT staff for Rayfield's book Fifty in 40: The Unofficial History of JWT London, 1945-1995. Also includes notes and a draft timeline. Tapes and master transcripts are closed to non-JWT researchers; see Use Copies of transcripts in boxes 1-2.
  - Interview transcripts (Use Copies); Luncheon, Individuals A-J (Box 1)
  - Interview transcripts (Use Copies); Luncheon, Individuals L-Y (Box 2)
  - Timeline and notes (Box 2)
  - Interview tapes and transcripts (Archival Masters); Luncheon, Individuals A-G (Box 3)
    RESTRICTED
  - Interview tapes and transcripts (Archival Masters); Individuals H-M (Box 4)
  - Interview tapes and transcripts (Archival Masters); Individuals P-Y (Box 5)
- Accession (1993-090), 1955-1986, 2 boxes
  Includes 1955 business reports relating to JWT London Office; 1985-1986 reports by David Campbell-Harris (JWT Area Director for Eastern Mediterranean and the Middle East] on trips to the Middle East.
  - London business reports, 1955 (Box 1)
  - David Campbell-Harris, 1985-1986 (Box 1)
  - David Campbell-Harris, 1985-1986 (continued) (Box 2)
- Accession (1998-0509), 1928-1993 and undated, 3 boxes
  - Letters of terms, circa 1928-1932 (Box 1)
  - Budget and billing, 1935-1937, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Memos on the role of Account Representatives, 1960s, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Management training and development program, 1965 (Box 1)
  - Representative Survival Kit, 1969 (Box 1)
  - Advertising Planning Methods, 1987 (Box 2)
  - Procedures 3: Account Management, 1993 (Box 2)
  - Procedures 13: JWT Training Policy, 1993 (Box 2)
  - JWT New Business Handbook, 1980s (Box 2)
  - JWT Identity Guidelines, 1990s (Box 2)
  - 50 in 40 manuscript draft copy, circa 1985 (Box 3)
    [An unofficial history of JWT London, by Tom Rayfield]
- Accession (801209B), 1968-1981, 1 box
  Various reports and publications.
  - Exercise T-Plan Europe, 1968 (Box 1)
  - Decimalization of the Currency in Great Britain, circa 1971 (Box 1)
  - JWT marketing Strategy, 1974 (Box 1)
  - Group K presentations, JWT International Seminar, 1970 (Box 1)
  - Ford ESO Account Work Summary, 1972 (Box 1)
  - Ford of Europe, 1972 (Box 1)
  - Managers Meeting minutes, 1973 (Box 1)
  - control Department Systems and Procedure, 1974 (Box 1)
  - Annual Management Assessment/Objectives, 1975 (Box 1)
  - A Tender for EURONET--An Initial Promotional Programme, 1977 (Box 1)
  - Middle East Report, 1981 (Box 1)
  - The Practice of Media, 1972 (Box 1)
  - Advertising and JWT in 1976, 1971 (Box 1)
  - Some Observations on Forecasting and Planning, 1973 (Box 1)
- Various Small Accessions 1960-2003 and undated, 2 boxes
  - 831103 (Box 1)
    - Photocopies of newspaper clippings relating to the listing of JWT Group stock on the London Stock Exchange, 1980s (Box 1)
  - 850205A
    - Materials relating to London Board Awayday/New Technology Bazaar, 1982-1985 and undated (Box 1)
  - 850315B
    - Group 8 (precursor of Contact Advertising, Ltd.) reports, 1968-1970 (Box 1)
  - 860611A
    - London stock plan, 1966, 1973 (Box 1)
  - 93-210
    - JWT and British Market Research Bureau (BRMB)--Factual Description in Outline, 1960 (Box 1)
    - Executive Summary of Continental European Annual Market Reports, 1970 (Box 1)
    - Advertising Industry and JWT Forecasts for 1970-1975, 1970 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous Additions (Box 2)
    - Public Attitudes to Advertising, report by Advertising Association,1996 (Box 2)
    - New Business, Tender for United States Travel Service Account, 1976 (Box 2)
    - Executive Briefs on key issues in advertising, reports by Advertising Federation, circa 1996 (Box 2)
    - Craft Skills, 2003 (Box 2)
    - Project Fossil briefing (Nuclear Electric), circa 1990 (Box 2)
    - Nuclear Electric: Harnessing the Power of Communications, circa 1990 (Box 2)
    - JWT Organisation and Resource for British Airways, 1995 (Box 2)
    - JWT A Global Agency, presentation to British Airways, 1995 (Box 2)
    - British Airways Worldwide Media Planning Guidelines, circa 1995 (Box 2)
    - J. Walter Thompson Financial Sector Conference, 1993 July (Box 2)
    - The Case for Advertising, presentation to Nuclear Electric, 1993 (Box 2)
    - Presentation on PPGH/JWT (JWT's Amsterdam office), 1994 (Box 2)
    - Agency People Development, Thoughts and Suggestions for Commercial,1993 (Box 2)
    - European and Asian Managers Meeting, 1995 Sept. (Box 2)
    - JWT Worldwide presentation, 1994 (Box 2)
    - WPP Group plc presentation, 1994 Jan. 12 (Box 2)
    - Inside Advertising presentation, Institute of Practitioners of Advertising (IPA), undated (Box 2)
    - Nuclear Electric presentation, 1992 June 7 (Box 2)
    - New Business pitch, Nuclear Electric, circa 1990 (Box 2)
    - Memoranda, Nuclear Electric new business pitch, 1990 (Box 2)
    - JWT Resources, prepared for British Airways, circa 1990 (Box 2)